Woodcock, Alfred H.; Papers ua902.028
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Scientific Research, 1937-1986; 2; 4.25 cubic ft.
  - Atmospheric salt sampling, 1957-1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 9)
  - Plueston of the Western Pacific - A.J. Savilov, 1958 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 10)
  - Physalia sailing, 1959-1970; 2.47 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 11)
    - a. Robert Bieri, "Dimorphism and Size Distribution in Velelia and Physalia"Nature, 1333-1334, 1959 October 24
    - b. Lisbeth Francis, "Design of a Small Cantilevered Sheet: The Sail of Velella velella"Pacific Science, vol. 39, no. 1, 1-15, 1985
    - c. A Russian publication of A. N. Cabnob?? In cyrilic, CCCP 1958
    - d. A Note to Dick Backus from A. H. Woodcock, 1961 March 1; typescipt
      Marked corrected copy, Subject: "Making Observations of the Sailing Direction of Physalia on the Next Chain cruise", three pages & two incomplete drafts of same.
    - e. G. O. Mackie from the Pacific Marine Station, California, titled "Factors affecting the distribution of Velella", 12 pages & 2 graphs
    - f. A graph of Woodcock's labeled "Observations of Physalia physalis dipping rate as a function of wind speed, Straits of Florida, March 1961 with ink and pencil notations
    - g. Reprint article, Charles E. Lane and Eleanor Dodge, "The toxicity of Physalia Nematocysts"Biological Bulletin, Vol 115, No. 2, 219-226, 1958 October
    - h. Reprint article, R. V. Southcott, "Venomous Jelly Fish"Good Health, South Australia, 1-6, 1960 January
    - i. Reprint article, C. W. Kingston and R. V. Southcott, "Skin Histopathology in Fatal Jellyfish Stinging"Transactions of the Royal Society for Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, Vol. 54, No. 4, 373-384, 1960
    - j. A Rejection letter from Nature for a mss, 1970 December 17
    - k. Reprint, J. B, Wittenberg, J. M. Noronah and M. Silverman, "Folic Acid Derivatives in the Gas Glands of Physalia physalis L". Biochem. J. 85, 9, 9-15, 1962
    - l. Proof with hand written corrections in pencil by Woodcock, "Note Concerning Physalia Behavior at Sea"Limnology and Oceanography, V. 16 (3), 551-552, 1971 May
    - m.
      Two drafts of the Notes (17 pages) article above (see 12) & correspondence (2 pages) with Dr. Yvette H. Edmondson, two of the letters are very amusing one from Woodcock to Edmondson explaining his difficulty in getting more data for the Note "The research vessel crew thought I was mad as it was" for spending that much time on the observations in a small boat, and Edmondson's note with reviewers comments concluding "I am amused to note that one of these referees apparently thinks of you as a meteorologist and the other as a biological oceanographer. It's always been my understanding of the legend that you're really a pomologist".
    - n. A negative and black & white photo of Physalia probably for use as an illustration if needed in the Notes article 12 above but not dated & negatives and four color photos of Physalia again probably taken during the observations for the Notes article
    - o. Article by Dorothy H. Miles, "The Left-handed Jelleyfish" Sunday Star Bulletin & Advertiser, for release Sunday, 1972 March 19; photocopy of typescript
      5 pages double spaced with hand written comments in Woodcock's ??? hand.
    - p. Two note cards with article citations & comments
  - Comparison of isopiestic and flame photometer methods, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 12)
  - Photo micrographs of steam cloud sample #15, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 13)
  - Steam cloud samples, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 14)
    November 2-3, slide 4 November 3-4, 1960.
  - Schults counts of particles in steam cloud, 1960 November 8 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 15)
  - Lab steam cloud sampling, 1960 November 17 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 16)
  - Particles from hot lava using saturated sea salt solution, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 17)
  - Comments about sustained swimming speeds of dolphins, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 18)
  - Volcano steam cloud study Hawaii, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 19)
  - Steam cloud particles photographs slide #15, 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 20)
  - Steam cloud particles slides #1 and #19 photo micrographs, ca. 1960 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 21)
  - Glacier variations and climate, 1960-1962 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 22)
  - Ice melt patterns, 1960-1965 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 23)
  - Record book no. 1, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 24)
  - New note about physalia, 1961 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 25)
  - Physalia chain observations, 1961; 2.62 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 26)
    - a. Two note cards on Sailing of P-p
    - b. Chart of Chain observations (cruise 17) Dr. R. H. Backus -pencil. 1 page
    - c. "Notes on Physalia, Chain Cruise 17 abstracted from journal of R. H. Backus, 4 pages
    - d. Ian A.E. Bayly to A. H. Woodcock, 1967 October 8
      Letter, discussing his research interests.
    - e. Advertising flyer with notes by Woodcock for Australian Inland Waters and their Fauna Eleven Studies Edited by A. H. Weatherly
    - f. Pencil equipment list and observations on sea surface and in tank, Undated; 1 page
    - g. Pen notes titled Chain 35 St. Thomas - Recipe, Brazil (Leg #1) P.M. O'W observations R. H. Backus, 1 page
    - h. Two note cards of citations on Edwards '66 and Savilov '67
    - i. 1 page note that information about Physalia work can be found in file "Data re Papers"
    - j. Reprint, Sammy M. Ray, "Gymnodinium breve: Induction of Shellfish Poisoning in Chicks", Science, Vol 148, No. 3678, 1748-49, 1965 June 25
    - k. 1 page double sided of notations in pencil, California, Japan, South Atl?, etc. some with totals
    - l., 1943 November 15; 1 page
      With name Clara Shoemaker (American Museum of Natural History) and counts for New Zealand "1 left", between Cook and Marshall Islands at Marembold "1 left" and a few other notations.
  - Rain recorder records, 1961 October 22-1961 November 30 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 27)
  - HDO, 1961-1962 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 28)
  - HDO in raindrops, 1961-1962 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 29)
  - Deuterium in raindrops Hawaii, 1961-1962 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 30)
  - Record book no. 2, 1962 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 31)
  - Salt induced convection and clouds, 1962; 1959 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 32)
  - Salt spray in hurricanes, 1962-1968 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 33)
  - Rain recorder paper, 1963 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 34)
  - Salt + Copters, 1963-1965 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 35)
  - Atmospheric sea salt, 1963-1966 (Box 5 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 36)
  - Smoke experiment pictures, 1964 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 1)
  - Salt convection, preliminary report on salt convection experiment results, 1964 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 2)
  - Lake sediment, radiocarbon dating, 1965-1967 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 3)
  - Melt patterns in ice over shallow waters, 1965 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 4)
  - Record book no. 3, 1965-1966 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 5)
  - Carbon 14 analysis proposal etc. (Waiau core), 1965-1966 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 6)
  - Older Lake W. reports, etc., 1965-1967 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 7)
  - L. Waiau sediment TC, 1965-1967 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 8)
  - Waiau Data, 1965-1967; 1970 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 9)
  - Waiau data, 1965-1968 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 10)
  - Waiau core, patterned ground in Waiau core, stone drift, unidentified photos, 1965; 1968; 1975 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 11)
  - Geochron laboratories, inc. (Waiau cores), 1966 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 12)
  - Record book no. 4, 1966-1967 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 13)
  - Soaring flight studies, 1966; 1952; 1945 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 14)
  - Waiau photos, 1966; 1978 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 15)
  - Record book no. 5, 1967-1968 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 16)
  - Latest version of Waiau paper, 1967-1969 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 17)
  - Record book no. 6, 1968-1969 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 18)
  - Patterned ground MK Hawaii, drill hole, plant biology, 1968-1977 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 19)
  - Waiau photos, 1968; 1978 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 20)
  - Lichen trace mineral results, Mauna Loa Mauna Kea saddle area, 1969 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 21)
  - Record book no. 7, 1969-1971 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 22)
  - Glacier variations and climate, 1969-1976 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 23)
  - Lake Waiau, 1969-1970; 1978; 1982 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 24)
  - Glacier variations and climate, 1970-1978 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 25)
  - Glacier variations and climate, 1970-1978 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 26)
  - Record book no. 9, 1971 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 27)
  - Record book no. 8, 1971 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 28)
  - Mauna Kea Juniper news note Lake W., 1971 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 29)
  - Record book no. 10, 1971-1972 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 30)
  - Record book no. 11, 1972-1973 (Box 6 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 31)
  - Record book no. 12, 1973-1975 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 1)
  - Mauna Kea "breathing", 1974; 1978 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 2)
  - Snow ablation forms, "nine perritente", patterned ground, 1975 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 3)
  - Record book no. 13, 1975-1976 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 4)
  - Record book no. 14, 1976 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 5)
  - Mountain breathing MK, water vapor from drill hole, deuterium, 1976 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 6)
  - Record book no. 15, 1976-1978 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 7)
  - Cape Cod canal fog, 1977-1982; 1959; 1962 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 8)
  - Lake Waiau core photos- 1978, old photos of sargassum lines and rain showers (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 9)
  - Record book no. 16, 1978-1982 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 10)
  - Geological Society of America Bulletin, pt. 2, 1979 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 11)
  - Cape Cod canal fog data, 1981 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 12)
  - Ice melt patterns, 1981-1982 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 13)
  - Hawaiian telescope project- environmental impact statement, 1982 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 14)
  - Mauna Kea summit area, September 1982, UK drill hole temp. data (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 15)
  - Cape Cod Canal, Buzzards Bay, MA [record book no. 18], 1982 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 16)
  - September 1982 latest "ice patterns" work Woodcock and Lucas (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 17)
  - Hawaiian astronomy station- environmental impact study, 1982 (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 18)
  - U. Hawaii Mauna Kea science reserve master plan (Box 7 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 19)
  - MB (mountain breathing), 1966-1980 (Box 8 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 1)
  - Mountain breathing revisited, 1966-1980 (Box 8 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 2)
  - MB (mountain breathing) [folder 2], 1967-1986 (Box 8 (2-Scientific Research), Folder 3)